Another offensive move that can come in handy, when you need a fast one, is the flick.
The flick can be hard to master, and I recommend that you practice on someone other than a person because flicking hurts.
Proper flicking technique does not land on the flat of the blade, it actually engages the tip, because of course, that's the only way you're going to land that touch.
A flick is exactly what it sounds like though, where you actually, you engage the wrist to do a fast, flicking motion with your foil.
The foil's the lightest and most flexible weapon, so it actually bends quite easily, and you can see there's a little bit of curve in the blade as I flick.
Which is, as it turns out, perfect for reaching over an opponent?s back and landing a hit, a touch on that hard to reach, hard to parry target area?
So, from the side, a flick looks something like this.
So, again, a fast attack, it darts out, it does engage that straight arm, but you can flick an opponent in the back, from in front of them very quickly, with the proper technique.
So practice on a wall, like the padded walls we have here, practice on a dummy.
Practice on something besides a person until you master that technique.
And even in play when you're doing it correctly, flicks are not comfortable, so be aware that someone, if you begin flicking excessively those are probably what those dirty looks are about that you've been getting.